-亲爱的  好好享受比赛哦  -谢谢
- Oh, hey, honey. Have a great time at the game. - Thanks.
什么在响
Oh. Why are you crunching?
通常  我是守规矩的人
Ordinarily, I'm a rule follower,
但是如果有人不准我
but when someone tells me I can't bring
自带零食进体育馆
my own snacks into their stadium,
我就要生气[坚果]了
that's when I get a little nuts.
这是个自由的国家不是吗
It's a free country, right?
这么说吧  让我不爽[薯片]的是
Let's just say it ruffles me...
某些蠢货[花生]叫我
when some goobers tell me...
在发薪日[糖]花上半天
I have to spend half my payday...
在他们的热狗上
on their hot dogs.
记得回来照全家福
Please, just remember the family portrait.
-摄影师只有一个小时时间  -好吧
- We only have the photographer for an hour. Okay? - Okay.
亲爱的  要不要去试试
And, sweetie, did you have a chance to
我放在你衣橱里面的白裤子
try on the white pants I put in your closet?
哦  长什么样的
Oh, what do they look like?
白裤子还能长什么样
Is there really a more clear way to describe white pants?
亲爱的  如果不合适
Sweetie, if they don't fit you,
你就是全家唯一没穿白裤子的人了
you're going to be the only one not wearing white,
然后你就像"沃尔多在哪里"一样明显扎眼
[美国儿童杂志上的一款游戏
读者要在一群人当中找出沃尔多]
实际上  沃尔多在哪里不会明显扎眼
Actually, "Where's Waldo?" doesn't stand out.
你很难找到他  那正是游戏乐趣所在
He's super hard to find. That's the challenge.
此次全家福对我来说很重要
This portrait is incredibly important to me.
而且  他就叫沃尔多  没有"在哪里"
Also, his name is just "Waldo."
我花了好几周时间才选到
I spent weeks trying to find
一个每个人都有空的时间
a time that works for everybody...
还有合适的摄影师
and finding the right photographer.
你向我保证会乖乖合作  好吗
So if you could just promise me that you'll cooperate, okay?
-我保证  -好吧
- I promise. -Okay.
-你想得真周到  -谢谢
- This is amazing that you're doing this. - Mmm, thank you.
-你太棒了  -谢谢
- You're wonderful. - Thank you.
过来
Get in here
-哎呀使不得  -哦
- Oh, no can do. - Oh.
-我爱你  -拜拜
- I love you. - Bye.
我的好内裤哪去了
Where's my good underwear?
问题应该是
The question is,
为什么你还有烂内裤  杰
why isn't all your underwear good, Jay?
你赚钱那么多
You make a nice living.
新来的佣人老是把我的内裤和曼尼的弄混
The new maid keeps mixing up my underwear with Manny's.
有一次我随便抓了一条
Put on the first thing I grabbed.
紧得跟止血带一样
It was like a crotch tourniquet.
-你得跟她说啊  -为什么让我说
- You gotta talk to her. - Why me?
喂  你们说一样的语言
Hola. You both speak the same language.
她是葡萄牙人  你知不知道
She's Portuguese. Do you know how offensive it is...
把我们混为一类人是很不礼貌的
that you put all of us in the same mixing pot?
抱歉  请代我给她道个歉  还告诉她
Sorry. Please apologize to her when you tell her not to
-不要把我的内裤  -我们语言不通
- put my underwear- - I can't talk to her!
-卢克呢  -我代替他去
- Where's Luke? - I'm going instead.
卢克有个家庭作业明天就要交了
Luke suddenly remembered a school project due tomorrow.
噢  太不幸了
Oh, that's tough.
但是这对他可能是不错的一课
But it's a good lesson for the kid.
你作了承诺
You know, you make a commitment,
-你得要兑现  -对
- you gotta follow through. - Yeah.
是什么作业
What is the project?
他要采访一个曾经生活在60年代的人
He has to interview somebody who lived through the 1960s.
不会吧
Oh, no.
喂
Hello.
是啊  卢克
Yeah, Luke.
当然  我记得我承诺过什么
Oh, sure. I remember what I said.
过来吧  好
Yeah, come on over. All right.
歌洛莉亚  你得带曼尼去看比赛
Gloria, you're gonna have to take Manny to the game.
好耶  曼尼  快点
Yay. Manny, vamos!
我还在穿衣服呢
I'm still getting dressed.
妈  我觉得我减肥有效果了
Hey, Mom, I think my diet's working.
我内裤都松了
My underwear won't stay up.
摩登家庭 第一季第二十四集
好吃  来
Oh, so delicious. Yes.
今天不和你去没关系吧
Hey, you're okay with me not going with you today, right?
有人请我周末去婚礼献唱
I have been hired to sing at a wedding this weekend.
我在一次精彩的卡拉OK
I was plucked from obscurity
演出后被别人选中了
after a particularly stirring karaoke performance.
所以说呢  我也算是专业歌手了
So I guess you could say I'm a professional singer now.
他们是以花代钱付给你的  所以呢
Well, they're paying you in flowers, so-
反正就算他们给钱  我也会拿去买花的
Well, I would've blown the money on flowers anyway.
他们倒是省了我的麻烦
They're saving me a step.
再说所有的歌后都有人献花
Plus all the great divas are rewarded in flowers.
然后还有支票
They're also given paychecks.
我不大擅长闲聊  所以呢
And I'm really bad at small talk, so-
我懂了  没什么问题
I get it. It's not a problem.
是吗  我看你一早上没说话
Are you sure? 'Cause you've been quiet all morning.
因为我得酝酿一下我的嗓子
It's because I'm resting my instrument.
好吧
Okay.
我看他是压力巨大
I feel tension.
科比  科比  这边
Kobe! Kobe, over here!
Kobe! Kobe! Over here!
需要帮忙吗
What can I do for you?
你喜欢当篮球运动员吗
Do you like being a basketball player?
不是吧你
Serious?
我紧张了  我没想到你会往这边看
I choked. I didn't think you'd look up here at me.
那下次准备下
Little preparation next time.
用用脑子好好想哦
It's a mental game.
懂了
Duly noted.
-好  -湖人队入场
- All right. - Your Los Angeles Lakers!
-怎么了  -楼梯坏了
- What's wrong? - That broken step.
全家福会因此被毁的
It's gonna ruin our whole family portrait.
我是这样想的  我兴奋得不得了
Okay, here's my idea. I'm really excited about it.
全家人都穿白色
The whole extended family, all dressed in white,
一字从上到下排开
in a single-file line down the staircase.
就像高速公路的汽车
Oh, like a line on the highway.
不是
No.
那跳台滑雪
Or, uh, a ski jump.
也不是
No.
我搞跳台滑雪干嘛
Why- Why would I want a ski jump?
不知道
I don't know.
我是想一家人在一张大床上
My idea was to have the whole family in a giant bed,
就像威利・旺卡一样
[威利・旺卡  《查理与巧克力工厂》人物]
那简直太"可笑"了
Yeah, but that's ridiculous.
应该是"可口"
"Ridiculicious."
我什么都没看到
I don't see anything.
所以是我疯了吗
So I'm crazy?
不  你  没有
No. You're... not.
你爸早该把这个楼梯修好的
Your father was supposed to fix that step.
妈  你对这些小细节太挑剔了
Mom, you're obsessing over the tiniest little thing-
这么说你也看到了
So you do see it, yeah.
不就照张相嘛  有什么大不了的
What is the big deal about this one picture?
亲爱的  我跟你说
Honey, you know what,
我不指望你能理解  但是
I don't expect you to understand, but-
这样  等你以后当妈了
All right, when you're a mom,
会感到时光如白驹过隙
everything goes by so quickly.
要不了多久  卢克就开始刮胡子了
In a minute, Luke's gonna be shaving,
艾丽克斯去上大学  你呢
and Alex is gonna be off at college, and you're gonna be-
你会做一些了不起的事情
you'll be doing something great.
我就是想时间定格在这一刻
I just wanna freeze this moment as it is right now.
-能理解吧  -能
- You know? - I do.
我知道我平时松松垮垮
I know I don't show it,
但是这个家庭对我来说很重
but this family's still the most important thing-
管它呢
Screw it.
我亲自来修
I'm gonna fix the bastard.
我倒要看看有多难
I mean, seriously, how hard can it be?
你老爸能行  那我也能行  对吧
If your father can do it, I can do it. Right?
好吧
All right.
我只需要
I just need to...
抬起来-
lift-
现在我看见了
Oh, now I see it.
我们的位置真棒
These seats are amazing.
你口袋里怎么有糖漏出来
Why you have candy coming out of your pocket?
不是不是不是
No, no, no, no, no.
-什么  -我自己带了零食
- Huh? - I brought my own snacks.
不是我小气  这是原则问题
Not because I'm cheap. It's a matter of principle.
再说冒着被人发现的危险其实挺刺激的
Plus I get a little rush from the danger.
淡定  装酷
Be cool. Be cool.
-什么  -淡定  看前面
- What? - Be cool. Just look straight ahead.
我感觉好极了  哦吼
I never felt more alive. Whoo!
我越搞越糟糕  但我没有惊惶失措
Okay, I just made it worse. I'm not freaking out though.
我打电话给你爸  问他怎么修
I'm gonna call your dad, and he's gonna tell me how to fix this.
-天啊  是老爸  -哪儿
- Oh, my God! It's Dad. - Where?
那里  科比的后面
Right there, behind Kobe.
-天啊  -真是太少见了
- Oh, my god! - How weird is this!
快点快点  想一件事情来吓他
Quick. Quick, tell me something to say that will freak him out.
-说我怀孕了  -不  那个可不能乱说
- Tell him I'm pregnant. - No, not gonna say that.
响了响了  真是太有趣了
Okay, here we go. How funny is this!
你好  我是菲尔  有事请留言
Hey, it's Phil. You know what to do.
真是"有趣"呀
Well, that was pretty funny.
天啊
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
天啊  天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
天啊  天啊
天啊  天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
天啊  噢
Oh, my God. Oh.
好多了  失陪一下
It's much better. Excuse me. Sorry.
喂
Hello?
家里进来一只鸽子
There is a pigeon in our house.
怎么办  怎么办
What do I do? What do I do?
你谁呢
Who is this?
-不搞笑  一点都不搞笑  -冷静
- Never funny. Not funny now. - Calm down.
我从小就是在动物的陪伴下长大的
You know I grew up around many animals.
有一次一只公鸡袭击我
One time, a rooster attacked me,
我妈把它脖子拧了  然后晚上就吃鸡
and my mom wrung its neck, and we had it for dinner.
你真会挑时间讲故事  速回来救我
Great time for an anecdote. Help me.
其实它更怕你
It's more afraid of you than you are of it.
鸽子什么都不怕
Pigeons aren't scared of anything.
电线他们都敢站
They stand on electrical wires.
你会没事的  米奇尔  只要你不
You're gonna be fine, Mitchell. Just as long as you don't-
那个  他们要开始了
You know what, they're starting.
我得挂了  拜拜
I gotta go. Okay, bye.
只要我不怎么  小卡
As long as I don't what? Cam?
只要我不怎么  我的个娘亲
As long as I don't- Oh, God!
酷  接吻镜头来了
Cool. The kiss cam.
如果镜头圈到了我们
Wouldn't it be embarrassing if the camera
-会不会很尴尬  -我们是亲戚
- was on us and then the crowd started- - We're related.
但没有血缘关系
Not by blood.
你敢碰我  就让你"血溅当场"
Touch me and there will be blood.
-我们不行  -你怎么了
- Not us. - What's wrong with you?
是接吻镜头
It's the kiss cam.
要是圈到我们  我们就得接吻
When it lands on you, you're supposed to kiss.
她是我岳父的二婚妻子
This is my wife's dad's second wife.
法律上没问题  但是很怪异
So legally okay, but still weird.
太尴尬了
That was awkward.
又是我们
And we're back.
来吧  又没什么大不了的
Oh. Ay! Come on. It's not a big deal.
多亏了来电显示
Thank God for caller I.D.
于是你不想接你老婆电话就可以挂掉
So you don't have to talk to your wife.
看我回来收拾你
Oh, we're gonna talk, mister.
我会慢慢慢慢说死你
We're gonna talk and talk.
老爸  妈妈在电视上看到你了  你死定了
Dad, Mom saw you on TV. You're dead.
是这样的  接吻镜头应该只针对
Here's the thing. The kiss cam is only supposed to be...
现场观众娱乐一下的
for the enjoyment of the people at the game.
电视上根本不该播
They never show that on TV.
人们在自己的比赛场上做什么
What people do in the privacy of their own sports arena...
是他们的自由
should be their own business.
66年的时候我在我爷爷的办公品公司打工
So in '66, I worked in my grandfather's office supply business-
就是墨水啊  订书钉啊  纸张之类的
you know, your ink, your staples, your legal pads.
我说得太快了吗
Am I going too fast for you?
我听得都睡着了
I fell asleep for a second.
你在60年代就没做过有意思的事吗
Did you do anything interesting in the '60s?
有一个夏天
Well, one summer,
我在姥爷的理发店里帮忙扫头发
I swept up hair at my other grandfather's barbershop.
-别折磨我了  -你想要什么样的故事
- You're killing me. - What do you want?
我也不确定
I don't know.
布莱恩・贝壳维斯的爷爷当年在华盛顿游行过呢
Brian Beckwith's grandfather marched on Washington.
阿蒂・贝壳维斯吗
Artie Beckwith?
那个整天里吧嗦  怨天尤人的怂货
He couldn't walk two feet without complaining.
他去华盛顿游行过
He marched on Washington?
他是这样告诉布莱恩的
He told Brian he did.
跟马丁・路德・金一起
With Martin Luther King Jr.
马丁・路德・金
Martin Luther King?
-你以为他的理发师是谁  -什么
- Guess who cut his hair. - What?
你知道马丁・路德・金的理发师是谁吗
Do you know who cut Martin Luther King Jr.'s hair?
卢克的老师怕是也不知道
Neither does Luke's teacher.
-所以理发店是在华盛顿啊  -是的
- So the barbershop was in Washington? - Okay.
-你还为其他名人理过发吗  -那当然
- Did you cut any other famous hair? - Oh, yeah.
肯尼迪家族  理查德・尼克松  各位宇航员
The Kennedys, Richard Nixon, all the astronauts.
你以为巴斯・奥尔德的外号是哪来的
[巴斯・奥尔德  人类首次登陆月球的宇航员之一]
酷毙了
Awesome.
*莉莉的屋里最好玩*
*We love to play in Lily's room*
*要不要牛奶无所谓*
*We don't need any milk*
好了  莉莉  你老爸是铁血真汉子
Okay, you know what, Lily? I am a man.
爸这就去厨房给你拿牛奶
I am going into the kitchen to get your milk.
*万福玛利亚*
*Ave Maria*
*满被圣宠者*
*Gratia plena*
*玛利亚  满被圣宠者*
*Maria, gratia plena*
*圣洁的天主*
*Ave, ave dominus*
*主与尔偕焉*
*Dominus tecum*
*女中尔为赞美*
*Benedicta tu in mulieribus*
*尔胎子耶稣*
*Et benedictus fructus ventris*
*并为赞美*
*Ventris tui, Jesus*
*万福玛利亚*
*Ave Maria*
有一次  威尔特・张伯伦来光顾了
[威尔特・张伯伦  美国男篮巨星]
他说"你能帮忙修下我朋友的头发吗"
He says, "Can you take a little off the top for my friend here?"
-竟然是猫王艾维斯  -不是吧
- And it's Elvis. - No way.
他是世上最了不起的歌手  除了西纳特拉
Greatest singer that ever lived, after Sinatra.
谁敢反驳我就跟他急
I'll fight any man who says different.
我老爸说最棒的歌手是彼柏・布莱森
My dad says the greatest singer who ever lived is Peabo Bryson.
那我只好找你老爸算算账了
Then I guess I gotta fight your dad.
是吧
Yeah, I guess.
卢克说外公要找你算账
Luke says Grandpa wants to fight you.
干嘛什么都跟我过不去
Why does everything have to suck?
我们还是改天照相吧
Let's just do the picture another day.
我脸上马上要冒痘痘了
I think I'm getting a pimple.
不行
No.
你知道我多辛苦才约到那位摄影师吗
Do you know how long it took me to book this photographer?
在壁炉那里照怎么样
Maybe by the fireplace.
行啊  旧时代的老人都喜欢在那儿画塑像
Yeah. That's a classic old-person spot for a portrait.
拉倒吧  墙的颜色太恶心了
Yeah, if I'd ever bothered to paint that hideous wall.
克莱尔是个完美主义者  这有时候是好事
Claire is a perfectionist, which sometimes is a good thing,
比如选个绝代老公什么的
like when it comes to picking a husband.
有时候就不太好了
Sometimes it's a bad thing,
比如大家都觉得某样东西很不错
like when everyone else sees something beautiful...
而她的眼里就只有那些丁点大的瑕疵
and all she sees is the teeny-tiny flaw.
不行  坚决不行
No. No.
不行
No.
喂  我的房子遭殃了
Hi. My house is a disaster.
能在你那里拍照吗
Can we do this picture at your place?
这个  怕是不太可能了
Yeah, that's- that's not gonna work.
所以
So-
再缠一圈吧  粘紧点  用点力
Maybe one more layer. And tight, really tight.
-爸  能再催催他们吗  -刚打过了
- Dad, can you call them again? - I just did.
他们在路上了  比赛打进加时赛了
They're on their way. Game went into overtime.
我知道  但是太阳都快落山了
I know, but we're losing the light,
而且摄影师
and the photographer's
10分钟后还要去个犹太男孩成人仪式
gotta get to a bar mitzvah in 10 minutes.
红酒  现在  你不是吧
Oh, red wine. Really? Now?
亲爱的
You know, honey,
我觉得你有点太神经质了
I think you're getting a little too uptight about this.
-我呼吸困难了  -你没事的
- It's hard to breathe. - Oh, you're fine.
你把他怎么了  他脸都绿了
What'd you do to him? He's turning blue.
只要他的衣服是白色的就行
But his clothes will stay white.
-我们回来咯  -谢天谢地
- We're home! - Oh, thank God.
曼尼  我们换衣服去
Manny, let's go change.
嘿  又看见我美丽的贤妻了
Hey, there's my beautiful wife.
我知道你生我的气
I know you're mad at me,
我也知道这泡沫手指无法弥补我的过错
and I know this foam finger can't make up for everything.
亲爱的  你赶紧换衣服
Honey, you just go change,
那事儿我们回头再说
and we'll talk about what you did later.
嘿  谢谢你买票给我们
Hey, thank you so much for those tickets.
歌洛莉亚说你们玩得很开心
Gloria tells me you had a real good time.
没没  我可没有
Not really. No, I didn't.
上苍作证  我爱你女儿
God, I love your daughter.
我到时候再回来
I should- I should come by
亲下这台阶  修好这台阶
and kiss that step- fix that step.
你说的好像我是故意把家里弄得一团糟一样
Oh, you're acting like I wanted to destroy the house.
不  我只是觉得奇怪
No. I just think it's odd
你毁掉的大部分东西
that the majority of things you destroyed...
都是我妈送给我们的
were sent to us by my mom.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
也就是说我和那臭脏鸟周旋的时候
So while I'm fighting off that filthy creature,
还会有时间停下来想  哎呀真好
I actually stop and say, "Oh, you know what,
总算可以借机毁掉那些
here's the opportunity I've always been looking for
庸俗不堪的东西了
to destroy our kitschiest objects."
庸俗不堪  她听到一定会很"开心"的
Kitschiest? Oh, she's gonna love that.
其实如果你跟着我去婚礼
If you would've come with me to the wedding,
这一切都不会发生了
none of this would have happened.
你是真生气了啊
Okay. So you are angry.
米奇尔  我懂的
Mitchell, I get it.
你讨厌扯家常  还不喜欢鸟
You're terrified of small talk and birds.
你一定很庆幸那小鸽子
You're just lucky that pigeon
没缠着你聊天气状况吧
didn't want to chat you up about the weather.
-你好  杰  -你们也好
- Hello, Jay. - Hello, guys.
老天  你怎么穿得跟"舞迷"节目的选手似的
Oh, God. Oh, you look like the guy from Dance Fever.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
丹尼・特里奥  俄亥俄州克里夫兰市
["舞迷"节目的主持人]
老爸  非要这样吗  我不是在夸你
Dad, really? That is not a compliment.
所以之前我才让你先穿上试试  转过去
That's why I wanted you to try those on earlier. Turn around.
今天不能拍照  我的痘痘越发明显了
The picture can't happen today. My pimple's getting worse.
我可怜的小宝贝  你还能站着吗
Oh, honey, I am so sorry. Can you stand?
-能  -那就得拍
- Yeah. - Well, then the picture's happening.
大家一定会紧盯着我不放的
It's all anybody's gonna see.
我看可不一定
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
你看见她穿的裙子了吗
Did you get a look at her dress?
什么  我看她裙子干嘛  我爱的是你
What? Why would I look at her dress? I love you.
邓菲太太  太阳就快下山了
Uh, Mrs. Dunphy, the sun is setting.
好的  这就拍
Okay. Yeah, this is happening.
大家  快来  我们出去了
Everybody, come on. Let's go.
小心点  我下午才给家具刷了漆摆外边呢
Be careful. I stained some furniture out there this afternoon.
可不是嘛  老爸
Of course you did, Dad.
还有什么需要注意的吗
Anything else I need to know about?
没准旁边邻居正忙着打彩弹呢
Maybe the neighbors on either side are having a paintball fight.
都看好了  我那睿智无比的老爹
Now watch this. Dad, in his infinite wisdom,
今天给家具刷了漆
stained furniture today.
千万别碰着了  还没干呢
Don't touch it. It's wet.
-快点快点  -别照了  亲爱的
- Hurry, hurry. - Put that down, sweetheart.
很好很好  大家都过来了  现在站这边
Okay. Okay, we got it. Now we're gonna go out here.
老天啊  你在耍我吗
Oh, my God! Are you kidding me?
那洒水器怎么关
How do- How do you turn the sprinklers off?
又问我  当然了  就因为我是拉丁人
Ay! Of course! Because I'm Latina,
我就该对花园  洒水器什么的了如指掌
I'm supposed to know everything about gardening and sprinklers!
他们装这东西的时候就你在
You were here when they installed it.
是诶  控制器在草坪那边
Ay, yeah. The box is across the yard.
你是说要跨过这片黄浦江吗
You mean your now-soaking-wet yard?
真好  彻底歇菜了
That's great. We are screwed.
不  还没
No, we're not.
我们还没出秘密武器呢
We haven't unwrapped our secret weapon yet.
拆弹特工--卢克小神童过去
Luke walks over there, Hurt Locker style...
关掉开关
flips the switch,
嘭  或者不嘭  水就关了
and boom- or not boom- water off.
好男儿志当英雄  儿子
Put the "he" in "hero," son.
拆弹专家  洒水器终结者还差不多
Hurt Locker? It's more like Squirt Locker.
不是吧  不搞笑吗
Really? That wasn't funny?
我真同情你们这群没幽默感的
I actually pity you guys.
没空庆祝了  都给我停
No time to celebrate! Stop it!
-我们时间不多了  -好的  大家
- We don't have a lot of time. - All right, everybody.
-请小个子的站前面  -先生
- If I can have the little ones down front- - You know what, sir?
不介意的话  我来吧
If you don't mind, I've got this.
大伙  都过来吧
Come on, people, let's get out here.
海莉  艾丽克斯  你们给弟弟拆胶带
Haley, Alex, I need you to unwrap your brother.
邓菲一家站这边
All right, I need the Dunphys over on this side.
爸爸  你站中间
Dad, you're in the middle.
米奇尔  小卡  莉莉站那边
Mitchell, Cam, Lily on this end. Okay.
-听我说  -怎么
- Listen. - Uh-huh?
亲爱的  我错了  如果你再次投入我怀抱
Honey, I screwed up, but if ever you're in my arms again-
-菲尔  现在不说这些  -就得现在说
- Phil, not now. - Yes, now.
我不想日后看到这张照片时
I don't want to look at this picture...
比如我80岁  而你早已与世长辞的时候
when I'm 80 years old and you're long dead...
还想到你拍照时心里深藏的怒气
and know that you were angry at me when we took it.
菲尔  回头再说行吗
Phil, we'll talk about what you did later.
好了  大家  请看这里
Okay, everybody. Eyes over here.
不关我的事  是她亲的我
I didn't do anything. She kissed me.
什么
What?
-谁亲了你  -歌洛莉亚
- Who kissed you? - Gloria.
-什么  -是接吻镜头[同音:亲了小卡]
- What? - It was the kiss cam.
你亲小卡做什么
Why did you kiss Cam?
不是  我亲了菲尔  他说必须那样
No, I kissed Phil. He told me I had to.
-不是这样的  -等一下
- No, no. - Okay, hang on a second.
这是在你无视
Was this before or after
老婆电话之前还是之后
you ignored the phone call from your wife?
那个你也看见了
You saw that too?
我们就不能先把相照了吗
Could we please just take the damn picture?
好了  大伙  再来一次
Okay. Everybody, one more time.
-你知道吗  我很生你的气  -我就知道
- Just so you know, I am angry with you. - I knew it!
-我靠  -今天对我来说很重要
- Oh, damn it! - It was a big day for me,
而他不参加的原因是他不喜欢扯家常
and he didn't want to go because he doesn't like small talk.
把你们这些小吵小闹
Would it be terribly inconvenient...
推迟那么几分钟就有那么难吗
to just postpone this hissy fit for a few minutes?
你知道吗  或许我们根本就
Ok, you know what? Maybe some of us don't
-不想今天拍照  -多谢
- want to take a picture today. - Thank you.
拜托了  克莱尔
And please, Claire,
别逼米奇尔做他不想做的事
don't try to make Mitchell do something he doesn't wanna do.
闭嘴吧  小卡
Oh, shut up, Cam.
好了  别闹了
Okay, stop it! Stop it!
大家都听好了  我真的好不容易才筹划好
Everyone, listen. This took me forever to put together,
所以我真的不在乎
so I don't really care
谁亲了谁  谁额头上长了痘痘
who kissed who and who's got a pimple on her head...
或者谁穿了超级不得体的裙子
and who is wearing an outrageously inappropriate dress.
我们要打起精神  假装一切正常
We are gonna get together and act like a normal family...
持续十分之一秒就行
for one-tenth of a freaking second,
现在就这么办
and we're gonna do it right now.
-快点  -别碰我
- Come on, let's go. - Get your hands off of me.
就不  就不  你怎样
No. No. Make me. Make me.
太荒唐了  你们两个对每件事都那么纠结
Ah, this is ridiculous. You're both uptight about everything.
你不想陪他去参加婚礼
You didn't want to go to a wedding with him
就因为不愿意和别人聊天是吗
because you didn't want to make small talk?
我就是这样认识歌洛莉亚的
That's how I met Gloria.
还记得我对你说的第一句话吗
Do you remember the first thing I said to you?
记得  "我喜欢巧克力
Yes. "I like chocolate,
我喜欢水果  但不喜欢两样加在一起"
I like fruit, but not together."
常青藤高材生  你忍不了是吗  还有你
You couldn't come up with that, lvy League? And you.
你要是不那么完美主义
You would be a lot happier if you weren't
就会活得开心得多
so obsessed with everything being perfect.
瞧瞧我们一身白  什么东西  板球队吗
Look at us here all in white. What are we, a cricket team?
告诉你吧  生活本就不完美  克莱尔
News flash. Life is not perfect, Claire.
现在都给我冷静下来
Now calm the hell down.
好吧老爸  很好  对你来说当然轻松
Okay, Dad, that's great, and that's really easy for you to say.
但你以为是我想这样吗
But do you think I like being like this?
并非如此
No, I don't.
所以如果你有什么良方
So if you have some quick-and-easy fix,
何不现在就说来听听
why don't you just give it to me right now?
-杰  -我的老天
- Jay! - Oh, my God.
看我的  宝贝
I- I got this, baby.
不  你干  你干什么
No. What did- What did you do?
现在两个人都弄脏了
Now two people are dirty.
三个
Well, three.
好吧  你自找的
Okay, you know what?
谁叫你说"庸俗不堪"
That's for "Kitschy."
泥巴大战
Mud fight!
别这样  别别  停下
No. Don't do that. No, no, no! Stop it!
大家都站好  都听话  别闹了
Everybody get back in line. Come on, guys, stop.
可恶  你们
Damn it. Damn it! Guys!
不好意思
Excuse me.
你们到底拍不拍了
Are we still doing this?
不  不拍了
No. No, we're not.
-现在拍吧  -准备好咯
- Now we are. - We're ready!
-说"茄子"  -"茄子"
- Say "cheese." - Say "cheese"!
68年我在理发店扫头发的时候
Back in '68, when I was sweeping up hair in that barbershop,
我曾幻想今后自己家庭的样子
I had this mental picture of the family that,
如果够走运的话
if I was lucky enough,
有一天我会坐拥完美的妻子  完美的孩子
one day I would end up with- perfect wife, perfect kids.
结果呢  我没那运气
Guess what. I didn't get any of that.
最后捞到这么一群二货
Wound up with this sorry bunch.
可我每天都对此充满感激
And I'm thankful for that every day.
大部分时候吧
Well, most days.
我还是就提猫王艾维斯的事好了
I think I'm just gonna go with the Elvis stuff.
换我也会
Yeah. I would.
右边点  右边点
Uh, to the right. To the right.
稍微往左一点点
A skosh to the left.
对了
There we go.
不管了  反正重刷墙壁的时候
Whatever. I'm gonna have to take the picture down
还是得把这幅照片取下来的
when I repaint the wall anyhow.
-杀了我吧  -什么
- Kill me now. - What?
我真是太幸运了
Don't know how I got so lucky.
爱你
I love you.
-我喜欢这张照片  -是啊
- I love that picture. - Yeah.
-相框那里是有个缺口吗  -没有没有
- Is that a chip on the frame right there? - No. No.
-我看得到  -亲爱的
- I can see it. - Honey.